<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DATAVA Consulting</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DATAVA Consulting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualizations</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Medical Clinic Map and Dashboard</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gun Data Dashboard</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Data Mining Presentation</title>
      <link>/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project4/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieving Lexile Levels in R</title>
      <link>/post/lexilelevels/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lexilelevels/</guid>
      <description>For those that don&#39;t work in education or aren&#39;t aware, there is a measurement for a child&#39;s reading level called a Lexile ® Level. &amp;nbsp;There are ways in which this level can be retrieved using different reading assessments. &amp;nbsp;The measurement can be used to match a child&#39;s reading level to books that are the same level. &amp;nbsp;So the company maintains a database of books that they have assigned levels. &amp;nbsp;There are other assessments that measure how well a child is reading, but I&#39;m not aware of any systems that assign books as comprehensively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning and The Boss</title>
      <link>/post/deeplearntheboss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deeplearntheboss/</guid>
      <description>I created a Twitter account which was inspired by a couple Twitter accounts that applied a particular type of machine learning technique to learn how two (at the time) presidential hopefuls spoke. I thought, why not see what a model like this could do with lyrics from my favorite rock n roll artist?
Long short term memory (LSTM) is a recurrent neural network (RNN) that can be used to produce sentences or phrases by learning from text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language Difficulty and Diversity</title>
      <link>/post/empty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/empty/</guid>
      <description>*For R users not interested in the post but the code, a markdown file is available on github. Thanks to Zuguang Gu and Bob Rudis for the &amp;lsquo;circlize&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;waffle&amp;rsquo; packages respectively.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying Arabic for about 10 months now and had some thoughts that I wanted to post about. It&amp;rsquo;s challenging, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know how challenging it was exactly when compared to other languages even though I knew it was on the more challenging end of the spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>/post/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Most organizations have data, some lots of it. The problem sometimes becomes what to do with data once you have it. As various tools have increased the ability for data to be collected it is critical to have the means to understand and interpret this information.
Our project experience includes finding relationships in data, building predictive models, providing unique visualizations, and mining information for patterns. Whether you need a report, data dashboard, map, or interactive graphic, our solutions can provide the insights you need.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>